🛮 000000000000 | 🗷 thisis@fakeemail.com | 🌴 themagicalmammal.vercel.app | ☑ themagicalmammal | 🛅 themagicalmammal

个人精力

A University of Leeds graduate student who is enrolled in the Data Science and Analysis programme. Dedicated to software engineering, having two or more years of expertise, and specialising in full-stack web development, algorithms, and machine learning. Searching mostly for Machine Learning, Data Engineer, and Python Development positions.

Education_

University of Leeds

Leeds, UK

MSc in Data Science and Analysis

Sept 2021 - Current

- · Head of School International Excellence Scholar
- · Working as a PAL Mentor
- · Courses: Data Science, Programming for Data Science, Knowledge Representation and Reasoning, Statistical Theory and Methods, Learning Skills through Case Studies, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Statistical Learning

Madhav Institute of Technology and Science

Gwalior, India

BTech in Information Technology

May 2016 - May 2020

- · Graduated with Distinction
- · Selected for Industrial Visit among the top of the class

Atomic Energy Central School

Indore, India

High School

Apr 2014 - Apr 2016

- · Passed with Distinction
- \cdot Specialised in Physics, Chemistry, and Maths with Computer Science

Work Experience_____

Indian Institute of Technology

Indore, India

Software Engineer

Sept 2020 - Aug 2021

- · Collaborated with a four-person team to develop a CNN model that utilised YOLO as a foundation to improve the accuracy of ambient lighting conditions in the Mobile net architecture.
- · Automated and optimised the data handling process for traffic signs, working with Ubuntu 20.04 did shell scripting, and employed other Linux tools.
- · Significantly boosted the model's accuracy by 60%, which was yielding an accuracy of 70-78% under Indian street light. The older models, had an accuracy of 10-15%.
- · Technical Skills: Python with PyTorch, NumPy, Matplotlib, Pandas, Scikit-learn, C++, Ubuntu Linux, Linux tools, Apt, Scripting, Git.
- · Soft Skills: Teamwork, Time Management, Communication, Presentation skills.

University Projects____

The Relation between GDP and IMR

Leeds, UK

University of Leeds

Feb 2022 - Apr 2022

- · Analysing data from 1960 to 2020 and discover patterns in the data that show trends between Gross domestic product per capita, Infant Mortality rate, Literacy Rate, and Industrial Development.
- Study cross-sectional, longitudinal, and among various countries to find variations in trends and get the historical data to back up the change in the trend of our data.
- · Specific case studies were traced back to trends seen in the UK and how they affected the GDP and IMR.
- · Technical Skills: Tableau, Overleaf, LaTeX.
- · Soft Skills: Time Management, Teamwork, Presentation skills, Report writing.

IPL Analysis

Leeds, UK

University of Leeds Nov 2021 - Dec 2021

- · Analysing data from 2008 to 2015 to discover patterns such as trends, correlations, and probabilities.
- · Finding the differences between the best teams and players in various fields, as well as their performance on the field and the opponents.
- · Technical Skills: Python with Pandas, matplotlib, Seaborn.
- Soft Skills: Presentation skills, Leadership, Teamwork, Logical Thinking.

May 31, 2024

University of Leeds Oct 2021 - Dec 2021

· Study of serial killers behavior with various motives such as convenience (did not want children or spouse), enjoyment, power, escape, or avoiding arrest.

- Finding patterns in their starting and ending ages (when they are caught) and other factors of killing, as well as how it varies with different motives.
- Technical Skills: R with ggplot2, tidyr, R Markdown.
- Soft Skills: Report writing, Logical Thinking, Critical Thinking.

Skills

Programming Python (Pandas, PyTorch, NumPy, Scikit-learn. etc.), R(ggplot2), PHP, C/C++, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL.

Miscellaneous Linux, Shell (Bash/Zsh), LTEX(Overleaf/R Markdown), Tableau, Microsoft Office, Firebase, Git.

Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation, Engaging Presentation.

Achievements_____

2019	319/340, Graduate Record Examinations (GRE)	India
2018	Elite, DBMS NPTEL Exam	India
2018	Elite, C NPTEL Exam	India
2019	Winner, Smart India Hackathon (SIH)	India
2014	Level 3, TablaNiketan Exam	India
2014	Level 1, National Talent Search Exam (NTSE)	India

Publications _____

Journal Articles

Conference Proceedings

Linux

Interests____

Cooking I love cooking. I am an expert in most Indian-style cooking, enjoy baking and making my own pizza.

Since 2017, I have been in love with Linux. I recently switched to Mac OS, which feels like a premium of

Linux.

Technical Writing I write descriptive blogs about Linux some of them are on my GitHub and Medium.

Art I have always enjoyed drawing since I was a child. Recently, I have shifted to digital art mostly on Deviantar

Video Games I always had the gaming gene. I mostly play on my phone and occasionally on my switch.

Swimming I started swimming when I was 12. Going through submerged things while holding my breath was the mos exciting part.

Languages _____

English Professional proficiency Hindi Native proficiency

May 31, 2024